Guide to the Papers of William Baskerville Hamilton, circa 1700-1975 RL.00495
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Alphabetical Files
  - Gimbels, 1939 (Box 56)
  - Ginn and Company, 1941 (Box 56)
  - Gipson, Lawrence Henry, 1949-1955 (Box 56)
  - Givan, Walker F., 1947-1950 (Box 56)
  - Glanville, J. Linus, 1940 (Box 56)
  - Glasson, W. H., 1934 (Box 56)
  - Gohdes, Clarence, 1937-1940 (Box 56)
  - Golden, Mrs. Stella, 1939 (Box 56)
  - Goodman, Victor M. R., 1938 (Box 56)
  - Goucher College, 1940 (Box 56)
  - Govan, Thomas Payne, 1941 (Box 56)
  - Government Printing Office, 1939 (Box 56)
  - Graham, Frank P., 1950 (Box 56)
  - Green, Fletcher M., 1945 (Box 56)
  - Green, William Mercer, 1934 (Box 56)
  - Greene, Dean W. K., 1938-1942 (Box 56)
  - Greenewalt, Crawford H., 1963 (Box 56)
  - Gross, Paul M., 1960-1965 (Box 56)
  - Guess, R. Malcolm, 1936-1951 (Box 56)
  - Guillot, Ed, 1942 (Box 56)
  - Guillot, Mrs. Ed, 1950 (Box 56)
  - Haffenden, Philip (Box 77)
  - Hale, Oron J. (Box 77)
  - Hales, Frances, 1939 (Box 77)
  - Hall, Arthur R., 1949 (Box 77)
  - Hall, Louise, 1940-1965 (Box 77)
  - Hall, Medora, 1939 (Box 77)
  - Hallowell, John H. (Box 77)
  - Halsell, Willie D., 1945-1946 (Box 77)
  - Hameed, SMA. (Box 77)
  - Hamilton, Holman, 1946-1954 (Box 77)
  - Hamilton, J. D T., 1941-1945 (Box 77)
  - Hamilton, J. G. de Roulhac, 1945 (Box 77)
  - Hamilton, Norman (Box 77)
  - Hamilton, Thomas, 1955 (Box 77)
  - Hamilton, William Baskerville:
    The William Baskerville Hamilton subseries is part of the Alphabetical Files series, and extends from box 59 through box 76. It also includes boxes 163 and 164.
    - Personal and Family Correspondence (Box 59, 60, 61, 62, 63, 76a)
    - Personal and Family Legal and Financial Papers (Box 64, 65, 76b)
    - Personal and Family Memorabilia, 1833-1840 and 1911-1968 (Box 65)
    - Appointment Books, 1955-1971 (Box 66)
    - Jackson High School Annual, 1924 (Box 66)
    - Memoranda for the Files, 1967-1969 (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964-1972 (Box 66)
    - Reviews, 1934-1947 (Box 67)
    - Reviews, 1948-1952 (Box 68)
    - Reviews, 1953-1968 and undated (Box 69)
    - Speeches and Talks, 1941-1968 (Box 70)
    - Trips to England, 1935-1960 (Box 71)
    - Trips to England, 1962-1968; Africa and Australia, 1957 (Box 72)
    - Writings, ca. 1930-1940 (Box 73)
    - Writings, ca. 1941-1959 (Box 74)
    - Writings, ca. 1960-1967 (Box 75)
    - Writings, ca. 1968-1969 and undated (Box 75a)
  - Hamilton, Mary Elizabeth (Boyd) (Box 76)
    These papers include letters and memorabilia from Goucher College, travel in U.S. and Europe, etc., dated 1928-1948. Also included is a blueprint of the Hamilton Residence on Cranford Road.
  - Hamm, J. K., 1945 (Box 77)
  - Hanna, A. J., 1941 (Box 77)
  - Harcourt Brace and Co., 1939-1953 (Box 77)
  - Hardwick, Lucile, 1938 (Box 77)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1938-1947 (Box 77)
  - Harrison, Pat, 1936-1941 (Box 77)
  - Hartley, L. C., 1942 (Box 77)
  - Hartzell, Earl D., 1940 (Box 77)
  - Harvard University, 1940-1948 (Box 77)
  - Hastings, H. G., 1941 (Box 77)
  - Hayden, Carl, 1944-1945 (Box 77)
  - Heartman, Charles F., 1945 (Box 77)
  - Hedderick, Vashti, 1958 (Box 77)
  - Hederman Bros., 1940-1945 (Box 77)
  - Henderson, Alfred J., 1937-1954 (Box 77)
  - Henderson, Cary Smith, 1955-1964 (Box 77)
  - Herrick, John W., 1947 (Box 77)
  - Herring, Dean H. J., 1939-1947 (Box 77)
  - Hill, John L., 1963-1964 (Box 77)
  - Himstead, Dr. R. E., 1939 (Box 77)
  - Hodgins, Bruce, 1959-1969 and undated, 2 folders (Box 78)
  - Holy, Clyde R., 1946-1951 (Box 78)
  - Hoffman, Prof. J. Wesley, 1956 (Box 78)
  - Hogan, William R., 1948-1949 (Box 78)
  - Holcomb, Gene, 1939 (Box 78)
  - Holdt, David M., 1964-1968 (Box 78)
  - Holt, Henry, and Co., 1942 (Box 78)
  - Holton, Prof. Holland, 1939-1947 (Box 78)
  - Home Building and Loan Assoc., 1945 (Box 78)
  - Honsinger, Robert W., 1952 (Box 78)
  - Hooper-Holmes Bureau, 1935 (Box 78)
  - Hoopes, Luther H., 1963 (Box 78)
  - Hoover, Calvin B., 1941-1944 (Box 78)
  - Hopkins, Everett H., 1961-1963 (Box 78)
  - Horne, Josh L., 1955 (Box 78)
  - Hotel Dupont, 1948 (Box 78)
  - Hotel Reservations, 1946 (Box 78)
  - Howard, Clinton Newton, 1960 (Box 78)
  - Howell, Bob, 1938 (Box 78)
  - Hubbell, Jay B., 1943-1945 (Box 79)
  - Huitt, Homer C., 1940 (Box 79)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1943 (Box 79)
  - Humber, Robert L., 1945 (Box 79)
  - Hume, Alfred, 1928-1941 (Box 79)
  - Hunter, Louis C., 1944 (Box 79)
  - Hyde, Henry, 1944 (Box 79)
  - Hyer, June, 1955 (Box 79)
  - India Office Library, 1960-1965 (Box 79)
  - Irving, W. H., 1957 (Box 79)
  - James, Joseph B., 1954 (Box 79)
  - Jarman, Pete, 1944 (Box 79)
  - Jenks, William A., 1957-1963 (Box 79)
  - Johnson, Allen, 1968 (Box 79)
  - Johnson, Cecil, 1939 (Box 79)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1968 (Box 79)
  - Jones, Anna, 1939 (Box 79)
  - Jordan's Book Store, 1939 (Box 79)
  - Journal of Southern History, 1939 (Box 79)
  - Judicial Office, House of Lords, 1938 (Box 79)
  - Junior Historians, 1953 (Box 79)
  - Kahle, John R., 1941 (Box 79)
  - Kendrick, Prof. B. B., 1940 (Box 79)
  - Kennow, Albert W., Jr., 1942 (Box 79)
  - Ketchum, Mrs. Mabel D., 1939 (Box 79)
  - Keusch, A. William, 1941 (Box 79)
  - Kimbrough, T. C., 1936 (Box 79)
  - Kirby Lithographic Co., 1944 (Box 79)
  - Kirwan, Albert Dennis, 1947 (Box 79)
  - Knaplund, Paul, 1958-1959 (Box 79)
  - Knight, Edgar W., 1945-1952 (Box 79)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., 1941-1956 (Box 79)
  - Konelin, Martha, 1940 (Box 79)
  - Kramer, Robert, 1952 (Box 79)
  - Krey, August Charles, 1941 (Box 79)
  - Kubicek, Robert Vincent, 1960-1966 (Box 79)
  - Laprade, William Thomas: (Box 80)
    - Letters, 1935-1968 (Box 80)
    - List of Printed Writings, 1952 (Box 80)
    - Dinner in Honor of Laprade,1953 (Box 80)
    - Newspaper Article, 1949 (Box 80)
    - Various Writings (Box 80)
    - Writings: Foundations of Greater Britain chapters 1-6 (Box 81)
    - Writings: Foundations of Greater Britain chapters 7-9 (Box 82)
  - Laing, Lionel H., 1957-1958 (Box 83)
  - Lamar Life Insurance Co., 1948 (Box 83)
  - Lambdin, J. Carl, 1948 (Box 83)
  - Lambert, B. W., Jr., 1945 (Box 83)
  - Lanahan, E. L., 1942 (Box 83)
  - Land, Augusta, 1944 (Box 83)
  - Landis, R. J., 1935-1952 and undated (Box 83)
  - Langer, William L., 1940-1943 (Box 83)
  - Lefler, Hugh, 1946 (Box 83)
  - Leith, James Andrews, 1954 (Box 83)
  - Levine, Bertram, 1944 (Box 83)
  - Lewis, Arthur Beverly, 1962 (Box 83)
  - Library of Congress, 1937-1957 (Box 83)
  - Lincoln's Inn Library, 1938 (Box 83)
  - Lippincott, J. B., and Co., 1943 (Box 83)
  - Little, Brown and Co., 1943-1946 (Box 83)
  - Littleton-Griswold Fund Committee of American Historical Association, 1944-1960 (Box 83)
  - Lockwood, Wendell N., 1952 (Box 83)
  - Long, J. W., Jr., 1939 (Box 83)
  - Longest, Christopher, 1941 (Box 83)
  - Longmans, 1938 (Box 83)
  - Lonn, Ella, 1947 (Box 83)
  - Lord Chancellor (Box 83)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1946 (Box 83)
  - Lye, William F., 1963-1965 (Box 83)
  - Lyell and Lyell, 1937 (Box 83)
  - Lyon, E. Wilson, 1939 (Box 83)
  - Mabry, Alex, 1941-1945 (Box 84)
  - McAllister, John, 1955-1957 (Box 84)
  - McCain, Paul M., 1952-1953 (Box 84)
  - McCain, William David, 1936-1962 (Box 84)
  - McCallum, C. A., 1957-1958 (Box 85)
  - McCardell, Ella C., undated (Box 85)
  - McCarrell, David K., 1938-1942 (Box 85)
  - McCarren, Senator Pat, 1943 (Box 85)
  - McCloy, Shelby T., 1939-1961 (Box 85)
  - McClutchie, Mrs. J. D., 1944 (Box 85)
  - McCool, Dr. Dick Cauthen, 1952 (Box 85)
  - McCormick, Richard P., 1948 (Box 85)
  - McDermott, Roger D., 1944-1947 (Box 85)
  - McFeaters, Capt. C. P., 1945 (Box 85)
  - McKenzie, Prof. L. W., 1950 (Box 85)
  - McKinney, Loren C., 1940 (Box 85)
  - MacLean, Guy Robertson, 1955-1969 (Box 85)
  - McLean, Ross H., 1940-1941 (Box 85)
  - McLeish and Sons, 1940 (Box 85)
  - McLemore, R. A., 1940-1946 (Box 85)
  - Macmillan Co., 1945-1949 (Box 85)
  - McMillen, James A., 1939 (Box 85)
  - McMurtrie, Douglas C., 1936-1940 (Box 85)
  - McNaught, J. C. R., 1939 (Box 85)
  - Macy and Co., 1945 (Box 85)
  - Maddox, Houston N., 1953 (Box 85)
  - Malone, Dumas, 1947-1958 (Box 85)
  - Malone, Thomas P., undated (Box 85)
  - Manning, Helen Taft, 1965-1967 (Box 85)
  - Manno, F. J., 1950 (Box 85)
  - Manuscripts, 1812-1840 (Box 85)
  - Markham, C. B., 1939-1951 (Box 85)
  - Marquette, C. L., 1945 (Box 85)
  - Marshall, Roger P., 1948 (Box 85)
  - Marshall, Theodora B., 1936-1945 (Box 85)
  - Martin, A. J., 1945 (Box 85)
  - Martin, Abbot, 1925 (Box 85)
  - Mason, Stevens T., 1948 (Box 86)
  - Massachusetts Historical Society, 1939-1940 (Box 86)
  - Massachusetts State Library, 1940 (Box 86)
  - Masterson, W. H., 1954-1959 (Box 86)
  - Mathews, Prof. Joseph J., 1936-1964 (Box 86)
  - Mathews, Marcia M., 1938-1943 (Box 86)
  - Matterson, Clarence, 1947 (Box 86)
  - Matthews, William, 1939-1944 (Box 86)
  - May, D. C., 1945 (Box 86)
  - Mayfield, Henry D., Jr., 1966-1967 (Box 86)
  - Meneely, A. Howard, 1940 (Box 86)
  - Merritt, Gertrude, 1957-1970 (Box 86)
  - Metcalf, K, D., 1954-1955 (Box 86)
  - Metcalfe, W. C., 1961-1962 (Box 86)
  - Methuen and Co., 1939 (Box 86)
  - Miles, Guy, 1941 (Box 86)
  - Miller, R. M., 1941 (Box 86)
  - Mills, Bonnie, 1944 (Box 86)
  - Mintz, R. E., 1945 (Box 86)
  - Miscellaneous, 1938-1969 and undated, 2 folders (Box 86)
  - Miscellany, 1935-1941 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi, Misc. Articles on undated (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Advertising Commission, 1937 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Art Association, 1946 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Department of Archives and History, 1936-1947 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Geological Survey, 1933 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Historical Society, 1945-1968 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Quarterly, 1960 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Society for the Acquisition and Dissemination of Useful Knowledge, 1803-1814 (Box 87)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1940-1953 (Box 87)
  - Mitchell, F. K., 1944-1946 (Box 87)
  - Mitchell, Fannie Y., 1968 (Box 87)
  - Mitchell, S. C. 1940 (Box 87)
  - Moffett, William A., 1962-1968 (Box 88)
  - Montague, L. L., 1939 (Box 88)
  - Montgomery, Clifford, 1944 (Box 88)
  - Montgomery, G. Rip, 1940 (Box 88)
  - Moore, Alice, undated (Box 88)
  - Moore, Edith Wyatt, 1936-1947 (Box 88)
  - Moore, Elliott L., Jr., 1947 (Box 88)
  - Moore, Mrs. John Trotwood, 1931 (Box 88)
  - Moore, Meredith, 1941-1944 (Box 88)
  - Moore, Ross H., 1937-1962 (Box 88)
  - Morgan, Thomas S., Jr., 1958-1962 (Box 88)
  - Morris, M. H., 1944 (Box 88)
  - Morris, Richard B., 1947-1951 (Box 88)
  - Morrison, A. A., 1951 (Box 88)
  - Morse, Theodore F., 1953-1956 (Box 88)
  - Morshead, Sir Owen, 1958 (Box 88)
  - Morton, Jack, 1953 (Box 88)
  - Morton, Louis, 1941-1949 (Box 88)
  - Morton, Richard L., 1944 (Box 88)
  - Mosser, Mrs. Philip, 1944-1945 (Box 88)
  - Mowat, C. L., 1960 (Box 88)
  - Moyerman, S., 1939 (Box 88)
  - Munroe, John A., 1948 (Box 88)
  - Munter, Robert L., 1962 (Box 88)
  - Munyan, Merrill, 1942 (Box 88)
  - Myers, Winifred A., 1957-1972 (Box 89)
  - Nasher, Ray, 1942-1944 (Box 89)
  - Natchez Democrat, 1941 (Box 89)
  - National Archives, 1940 (Box 89)
  - National Broadcasting System, 1941-1945 (Box 89)
  - National Campaign Committee, 1932 (Box 89)
  - National Conference of Bar Examiners, 1952 (Box 89)
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1938-1940 (Box 89)
  - National Geographic Society, 1945 (Box 89)
  - Naval Officer Procurement, Office of, 1943 (Box 89)
  - Neal, Catherine, 1946 (Box 89)
  - Nelson, Duncan, 1951 (Box 89)
  - Nelson, Ernest William, 1936-1964 (Box 89)
  - Nelson, Ronald R., 1965-1969 (Box 89)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1952 (Box 89)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1948 (Box 89)
  - New York Public Library, 1946-1947 (Box 89)
  - New York Times, 1940-1959 (Box 89)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1945-1959 (Box 89)
  - New York University, School of Law, 1947-1948 (Box 89)
  - New York University Press, 1944 (Box 89)
  - New Yorker, 1946 (Box 89)
  - Newhouse, W. John, 1952 (Box 90)
  - Newman, Louis E., 1939 (Box 90)
  - Nichols, Roy F., 1948 (Box 90)
  - Nicholson, S. J., 1939 (Box 90)
  - Nigeria 1957-1971 (Box 90)
  - N.C. English Teachers Assoc., 1954-1955 (Box 90)
  - N.C. Historical Association, 1943-1949 (Box 90)
  - N.C. Historical Markers Committee, 1954-1961 (Box 90)
  - N.C. State Literary and Historical Assoc., 1947-1948 (Box 90)
  - Norwig, George W., 1947 (Box 90)
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1948 (Box 90)
  - Novick, Jerome F., 1943 (Box 90)
  - Nuermberger, Ruth K., 1943-1961 (Box 90)
  - Nunn, Grady H., 1957-1958 (Box 90)
  - O'Brien, Thomas D., Jr., 1941-1942 (Box 90)
  - Odell, Robert H., 1951 (Box 90)
  - Odgers, Merle M., 1956 (Box 90)
  - Ogden, J. P., 1941 (Box 90)
  - Oklahoma Historical Society, 1941 (Box 90)
  - Oldham, Edward A., 1945 (Box 90)
  - Ormsby, Miss M. A., 1966-1967 (Box 90)
  - Overdyke, W. Darrell, 1951 (Box 90)
  - Owsley, Frank L., 1937 (Box 90)
  - Oxford University Press, 1939-1961 (Box 90)
  - Oyler, Helen, 1946 (Box 90)
  - Pace, Antonio, 1947 (Box 91)
  - Packard, Highland Bryant, 1961-1964 (Box 91)
  - Packard, Sidney R., 1940 (Box 91)
  - Painter, Sidney, 1940-1959 (Box 91)
  - Pargellis, Stanley, 1953-1954 (Box 91)
  - Parker, Harold T., 1968-1971 (Box 91)
  - Parker, Harold T. Textbook, 1950 (Box 91)
  - Parker, Thomas Fleming, 1951 (Box 91)
  - Parks, Joseph, 1946 (Box 91)
  - Paschal, George W., 1948 (Box 91)
  - Passport Bureau, 1938 (Box 91)
  - Patrick, Ben M., 1940 (Box 91)
  - Patrick, R. W., 1958 (Box 91)
  - Payne, Ethel (WPA), 1940-1941 (Box 91)
  - Payne, Mrs. John, 1956 (Box 91)
  - Peacock, John R., 1953-1954 (Box 91)
  - Pearson and Crain, 1938 (Box 91)
  - Peckham, Howard, 1942 (Box 91)
  - Pegg, C. H., 1948 (Box 91)
  - Pennsylvania Hotel, 1946-1947 (Box 91)
  - Perry, Marvin, 1959 (Box 91)
  - Perry, Percival, 1963 (Box 91)
  - Peters, Frank A., 1944 (Box 91)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1964-1966 (Box 91)
  - Philbrick, Francis S., 1937-1938 (Box 91)
  - Phillips, C. E., and Son, 1939 (Box 91)
  - Photo Reproducing Equipment Co., 1944 (Box 91)
  - Piney Woods School, 1945 (Box 91)
  - Polier, Arthur, 1949-1950 (Box 91)
  - Pomeroy, Earl H., 1949 (Box 91)
  - Pope, Warren H., 1946 (Box 91)
  - Popper, Annie M., 1940 (Box 91)
  - Porter, Earl 1960-1969 (Box 92)
  - Porter, Henry P., Jr., 1965-1966 (Box 92)
  - Porter, Henry P., Jr., Letters to Parents, 1965 (Box 92)
  - Posey, Walter B., 1946-1951 (Box 92)
  - Posner, Ernst, 1953 (Box 92)
  - Post Cards, 1933-1938 (Box 92)
  - Potter, David M., 1945-1948 (Box 92)
  - Predmore, R. L. 1963-1965 (Box 92)
  - Pre-Legal Education, 1948-1950 (Box 92)
  - Prentice-Hall, 1947-1949 (Box 92)
  - President of the U.S., 1940-1951 (Box 92)
  - Price, K. G. 1945 (Box 92)
  - Pruitt, Olga Reed 1948 (Box 92)
  - Putnam's, G. P., Sons, 1938 (Box 92)
  - Qantas Airways, 1957 (Box 92)
  - Quintana, Ricardo B. 1939 (Box 92)
  - Quynn, William and Dorothy, 1939-1949 (Box 92)
  - Raines, G. N., 1951-1969 (Box 93)
  - Rainwater, Percy Lee, 1931-1940 (Box 93)
  - Ramsey, John F., 1949 (Box 93)
  - Rankin, Robert S., 1935 (Box 93)
  - Read, James Morgan, 1940 (Box 93)
  - Red Cross Drive, 1946 (Box 93)
  - Reed, Roy T., 1944 (Box 93)
  - Reeves, R. N., 1940 (Box 93)
  - Research Triangle (see boxes 94-95) (Box 93)
  - Reynolds, Nathan 1942 (Box 93)
  - Reynolds, Senator Robert 1939-1941 (Box 93)
  - Rich, Elizabeth 1942 (Box 93)
  - Ricketts, Mrs. B. R. 1945 (Box 93)
  - Rinehart and Co., 1947-1952 (Box 93)
  - Rivera, Rodolfo 1939-1963 (Box 93)
  - Roberts, J. L. 1939-1945 (Box 93)
  - Roberts, Mrs. John C., Jr. 1944 (Box 93)
  - Roberts, Dr. L. E. 1951 (Box 93)
  - Robinson, John F. 1937-1946 (Box 93)
  - Robinson, Lionel and Philip (Earl of Kimberley) 1958-1959 (Box 93)
  - Robinson, Ralph 1946 (Box 93)
  - Robison, Dan M. 1946 (Box 93)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 (Box 93)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor 1945 (Box 93)
  - Ropp, Theodore 1940 (Box 93)
  - Roseberry, James Royal 1966 (Box 93)
  - Rowland, Dunbar and Mrs. Dunbar 1934-1942 (Box 93)
  - Rowse, Alfred Leslie 1956 (Box 93)
  - Royal Commonwealth Society (Box 93)
  - Library Notes and Accessions, 1959 (Box 93)
  - Ruff, Hazel 1940 (Box 93)
  - Russell, J. C. 1941 (Box 93)
  - Rutherford, James 1956-1961 (Box 93)
  - Rutledge, Anna Wells 1940-1941 (Box 93)
  - Research Triangle, 1955-1970 (Box 94 and 95)
    Includes drafts of writings on the Research Triangle dated 1965-1966, and clippings dated 1965-1969.
  - St. Paul, John, Jr. 1947 (Box 96)
  - St. Phillips Church, 1943-1947 (Box 96)
  - Salvation Army, 1966 (Box 96)
  - School of Library Science, U.N.C., 1940 (Box 96)
  - Schultz, Harold J. 1956 (Box 96)
  - Schuster, Sir Claude 1938 (Box 96)
  - Scientific Aids to Learning, Committee on 1940 (Box 96)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1939-1944 (Box 96)
  - Sealey, L. B. 1940-1949 (Box 96)
  - Searcy, Hubert 1937-1960 (Box 96)
  - Secretary of State, 1942 (Box 96)
  - Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, 1939 (Box 96)
  - Sensabaugh, Leon F. 1953-1957 (Box 96)
  - Shanks, Henry T. 1946-1953 (Box 96)
  - Sharp, Mrs. W. Q. 1945 (Box 96)
  - Shepherd, Harold 1947-1949 (Box 96)
  - Sherwood, Robert E. 1951 (Box 96)
  - Shryrock, Richard H. 1941-1968 (Box 96)
  - Shuff, Mrs. C. W. 1940 (Box 96)
  - Silver, James W. 1946-1957 (Box 96)
  - Simester, Don 1942 (Box 96)
  - Sink, R. C. 1962 (Box 96)
  - Siousatt, St. George L. 1945 (Box 96)
  - Skaggs, Professor M. L. 1949 (Box 96)
  - Smiley, David L. 1965-1966 (Box 97)
  - Smith, B. L. 1953 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Culver H. 1938-1956 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Frank 1941 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Mrs. Hazen 1945 (Box 97)
  - Smith, John H., Draft of Colonial Cadet, 1966-1969 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Mrs. L. A., 1934-1947 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Martha R., 1939 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Rhea Marsh, 1940 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Robert S., 1947-1949 (Box 97)
  - Smith, Willis, 1949-1950 (Box 97)
  - Sneed, Pearl, 1945-1955 (Box 97)
  - Snyder, Major, 1942 (Box 97)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1942-1956 (Box 98)
  - Southern Historical Association--At end of S's (Box 98)
  - Southern Railway, 1944 (Box 98)
  - Southern Review, 1936 (Box 98)
  - Spears, Marshall T., 1945 (Box 98)
  - Spears, Mrs. Marshall T., 1943 (Box 98)
  - Spencer, Rt. Hon. Earl, 1958-1965 (Box 98)
  - Spengler, Joseph J.,1940and1972 (Box 98)
  - Spiro, Robert H., 1953-1957 (Box 98)
  - Spivey, Lydia, 1968 (Box 98)
  - Stabler, Caxey V., 1954 (Box 98)
  - Stackpole, Stephen, 1965 (Box 98)
  - Stanford University, 1942 (Box 98)
  - States Rights Party, 1948 (Box 98)
  - Stein, Luther R., 1945 (Box 98)
  - Stephens, B. Nelson, 1945-1958 (Box 98)
  - Stephenson, George, 1936-1938 (Box 98)
  - Stephenson, Wendell H., 1935-1964 (Box 98)
  - Stevens, Harry R., 1949 (Box 98)
  - Stevenson Campaign at Duke, 1952 (Box 98)
  - Stewart, Robert Percy, 1940 (Box 98)
  - Still, Bayrd, 1941-1946 (Box 98)
  - Stokes, Eric, 1962 (Box 98)
  - Strode, Hudson, 1956 (Box 98)
  - Stroupe, Henry S., 1947-1956 (Box 98)
  - Sugg, Dr. Eugene S., 1939 (Box 98)
  - Swarthmore College Friends Historical Library, 1948 (Box 98)
  - Swearingen, Prof. M., 1938-1949 (Box 98)
  - Sweet and Maxwell, Ltd., 1936 (Box 98)
  - Sydnor, Charles S., 1931-1953 (Box 98)
  - Southern Historical Association (Box 99)
    - Meetings 1936-1959 (Box 99)
    - European Section 1940-1967 (Box 100)
    - Session on Law and the Historian, 1963 (Box 100)
  - Tate, Caroline Gordon, undated (Box 101)
  - Taylor, Orville W., 1956-1969 (Box 101)
  - Taylor Hall, 1964-1965 (Box 101)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Assoc., 1939-1948 (Box 101)
  - Third Chancery Court District (Miss.), 1936 (Box 101)
  - Thomas, Mary Elizabeth, 1950 (Box 101)
  - Thompson, Allen C., 1940-1949 (Box 101)
  - Thompson, E. Bruce, 1946 (Box 101)
  - Thompson, Leonard M., 1960-1966 (Box 101)
  - Tilley, Nannie M., 1940-1959 (Box 101)
  - Topper, Annie M., 1940 (Box 101)
  - Torray, Robert, 1960-1962 (Box 101)
  - Townsley, W. A., 1963-1964 (Box 101)
  - Travel Bibliography undated (Box 101)
  - Triangle Blue Print Co., 1939 (Box 101)
  - U.S. Navy, 1943 (Box 101)
  - University Microfilms, Ltd., 1958-1964 (Box 101)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1945 (Box 101)
  - University of London, 1935 (Box 101)
  - University of Mississippi. History Dept., 1958-1960 (Box 101)
  - University of N.C. Summer Session, 1953 (Box 101)
  - University of the South, 1936 (Box 101)
  - Upchurch, W. M., Jr., 1941-1960 (Box 101)
  - Upshaw, John R., 1939 (Box 101)
  - V-E Day and V-J Day, 1945 (Box 102)
  - Valinger, Leon de, Jr., 1949 (Box 102)
  - Van Deusen, Glyndon G., 1948 (Box 102)
  - Van Dusen, A. E., 1943-1945 (Box 102)
  - Van Nostrand, D., Company, 1940-1943 (Box 102)
  - Vandenburg, Senator Arthur, 1945 (Box 102)
  - Vanderbilt, Arthur T., 1935-1957 (Box 102)
  - Vanderbilt, Arthur T. (George Warren), 1938-1940 (Box 102)
  - Vanguard Press, 1946 (Box 102)
  - Walker, Kenneth F., 1957-1958 (Box 103)
  - Wallace, J. T., 1935 (Box 103)
  - Walters, Louise, undated (Box 103)
  - Wannamaker, Dean W. H., 1941-1953 (Box 103)
  - War Bond Drive, 1943-1944 (Box 103)
  - War Day, 1942 (Box 103)
  - War Department, 1940-1942 (Box 103)
  - War Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 103)
  - Ward, 1938 (Box 103)
  - Ward, John M., 1957-1968 (Box 103)
  - Ward, Russel, undated (Box 103)
  - Warlick, R. A., 1956 (Box 103)
  - Watkins, Will, 1937-1940 (Box 103)
  - Watson, J. Steven, 1961-1962 (Box 103)
  - Watson, Richard L., 1940-1968 (Box 103)
  - Wellborn, Mary Moss, 1945-1968 (Box 103)
  - Welty, Eudora,1937-1968and undated (Box 103)
  - Werber, William M., 1947-1968 (Box 103)
  - Werk, George B., 1950-1952 (Box 103)
  - West Indies, University of. History Dept., 1965-1966 (Box 103)
  - Weston, Corinne Comstock, 1948-1958 (Box 103)
  - Wharton, Vernon L., 1948-1960 (Box 103)
  - Wheeler, Sen. Burton K., 1940 (Box 103)
  - Whipple, Dean George H., 1947 (Box 103)
  - White House Secretariat, 1939 (Box 103)
  - Whiteside, Andrew G., 1954 (Box 103)
  - Widener Memorial Library, 1940 (Box 104)
  - Wienefeld, R. H., 1954-1964 (Box 104)
  - Wiley, Bell I., 1947 (Box 104)
  - Wilkinson, A. A., 1943 (Box 104)
  - Willging, Eugene P., 1955 (Box 104)
  - William and Mary Quarterly, 1947-1955 (Box 104)
  - Williams, J. D., 1956-1960 (Box 104)
  - Williams, Mrs. Ruth J., 1945 (Box 104)
  - Williams, T. Harry, 1947 (Box 104)
  - Williams Bookstore, 1940 (Box 104)
  - Williamsburg Seminar 1960 (Box 104)
  - Willkie, Wendell, 1940 (Box 104)
  - Willson, David Harris, 1939-1962 (Box 104)
  - Wilson, Robert R.,1942or1943 (Box 104)
  - Wimberley and Gregory, 1939 (Box 104)
  - Wittke, Carl, 1941 (Box 104)
  - Wolf, John B., 1941 (Box 104)
  - Wolfe, Karl F., 1945 (Box 104)
  - Wood, Charles K., 1961 (Box 104)
  - Woodfin, Miss Maude H., 1942-1943 (Box 104)
  - Woodward, Ellen S., 1944-1946 (Box 104)
  - Worcester Blue and Photo Print Co., 1939 (Box 104)
  - Worley, John S., 1943 (Box 104)
  - Wright, Dudley, 1939 (Box 104)
  - Wright, Grover C., 1949 (Box 104)
  - Wright, Louis B., 1940-1962 (Box 104)
  - Wright Howes, 1946 (Box 104)
  - Young, Stark, 1934-1935 (Box 104)
- Printed Material
  Printed materials have been filed in the alphabetical folders when they were related to the persons, organizations, or topics represented in those folders.
  - Duke University (including Duke Endowment),1931-1972 (Box 105-110)
  - Great Britain (1932-1969), Africa (1950-1968), Australia (1886), and Malaysia (1965) (Box 111)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 112 and 113)
  - Mississippi 1866-1968 (Box 114 and 115)
  - New Zealand 1938-1963 (Box 116)
- Pictures